Manish Ranjan Mahanta

Bengaluru, KA | (91) 8000537300 | Email | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

Summary

A detail-oriented, versatile professional with **7.5+** years of Software development experience in architecting, leading, developing and deploying several enterprise grade applications, web projects & services in C# .NET + Razor / SPA.js. Fast-learner with a can-do attitude and a passion for developing simple strategies to solve complex problems.

Skills

• C# .NET

DSA

- Team Leader
- Azure & AWS Cloud

- MVC | REST API
- DevOps CI/CD
- Mentor

• Unit Test (NUnit)

- System Design
- Agile (SCRUM)
- RESTful API

Work Experience

Unisys India Pvt. Ltd, Bengaluru, KA

06/2016 - present

04/2021 – present

Senior Engineer

<u>Diagnostic Collection Suite</u> - RESTful APIs | C# .NET Core | SPA.js | MariaDB

• Led architecture & development of automated detection & diagnostic collection API, which improved average issue/bug turnaround time by 25%.

<u>Version Compliance Suite</u> - RESTful APIs | C# .NET Core | Razor Pages | MariaDB

• Led architecture & development for 2nd release, redesigning core - monitoring & reporting API and leveraging algorithmic improvements & design patterns, improving reporting output by **10x** & performance by 15%

AWS, Azure & VMware Cloud Adoption

- Drove roadmap planning for adopting & supporting VMware, AWS & Azure Cloud Platform collaborating with global & external leaders, which was the key highlight in acquisition of \$144 million client contract.
- SME & Team Leader for multiple teams to evaluate AWS, Azure & VMware Cloud platform, exploring possibilities & challenges in architecting & migrating OS stack, increasing availability to 99.99%.

Mentor Experience

- Fostered a team-culture of *doing it right the first time* by emphasizing on careful design & analysis and setting high code standards by stringent reviews & high coverage Unit Tests.
- Mentored associates by involving them in architectural and high-level bug analysis discussions to incorporate *open, honest and inclusive approach* to problem solving, incorporating essential system design skills.

Systems Engineer 07/2017 – 03/2021

Soft Tape Manager - RESTful APIs | C# .NET Core | SPA.js | SQL Server

- Team leader for complete SDLC of second release, responsible for development of full-stack, communicating with other teams to deliver high quality solution from initial product design to production, improving Suite revenue by 15% YoY, bringing in \$12.6 million contract. [Silver Recognition Award]
- Improved DevOps process reducing build time 25% by strategically restructuring pipelines.

Associate Engineer

06/2016 – 07/2017

• Led core tape emulation mechanism architecture and development, leveraging CIFS, Windows APIs, Linux Shell Scripts for data-plane, along with RESTful API for control plane. [Patent - US 15/933,662]

Projects

BetterCoder.in - Open Source | ASP .NET MVC | React.js | Azure SQL

• Goal to upskill the core Computer Science competencies with practice roadmap for reinforcing data-structures and algorithms with carefully curated and categorized LeetCode questions with solutions.

OpenAl Voice Assistant - Python | Open Al GPT 3 API

• A minimalist interactive voice assistant which listens to the user voice commands, analyzes it and responds considering the context set by previous inputs as well, in the same language.

Education